Every moment matters.
Prisoners is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Denis Villeneuve.
Keller Dover is facing every parent’s worst nightmare.
His six-year-old daughter, Anna, is missing, together with her young
friend, Joy, and as minutes turn to hours, panic sets in.
The only lead is a dilapidated RV that had earlier been parked on their street.
Keller Dover, played by Hugh Jackman.
Detective Loki, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Nancy Birch, played by Viola Davis.
Grace Dover, played by Maria Bello.
Franklin Birch, played by Terrence Howard.
Holly Jones, played by Melissa Leo.
Prisoners is a 2013 American psychological thriller film directed by
Denis Villeneuve and written by Aaron Guzikowski.
The film has an ensemble cast including Hugh Jackman, Jake Gyllenhaal, Viola
Davis, Maria Bello, Terrence Howard, Melissa Leo, and Paul Dano.
The film follows the abduction of two young girls in Pennsylvania and
the subsequent search for the perpetrator by the police.
After police arrest a young suspect and release him, the father of
one of the daughters takes matters into his own hands.
Prisoners premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on August 30, 2013,
and was released to theaters on September 20, 2013.
The film was a financial and critical success, grossing $122 million
worldwide against a production budget of $46 million.
It was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the top 10 films of 2013, and at the 86th Academy Awards, Roger Deakins was
nominated for Best Cinematography in addition to receiving a nomination from the American Society of Cinematographers.
The film explores themes of pennsylvania, usa,
kidnapping, hostage, detective, maze.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.